

Domenico Camasta

✓ domenicocamasta@gmail.com 📞 3701522690 🔮 Via F. Baracca 8 🛗 29/12/1983

■ Italian

♣ He/Him ★ portfolio.devcrumbs.com ♠ d-cmst

Profile

I'm a mathematician by education and self-taught software developer for passion, with over 10 years of experience building full-stack web applications with Python, JavaScript, React, Node.js and PHP. My expertise also includes systems administration and databases management/optimization.

Professional Experience

Developer, *UserTesting* □

2018 - 12/2022

Creating and executing usability tests to evaluate the ease of use, efficiency, and overall user experience of software products: designing test plans, coding test scripts, recruiting test participants, and analyzing test results.

UK | Germany | Remote

Developer, Appen Ltd Chatbot software development. 2020 - 2022

Project Manager, *UniD Formazione* □

2015 - 2018

Remote

Development, deployment and system administration for the company web applications.

Borgo Maggiore, RSM

Teacher, MIUR □

2011 - 2014

Mathematics/Logic teacher for high school and university students.

Verona, Italy

Languages

Italian Native

English

TOEFL 2020

Education

PhD, Università "La Sapienza"

2007 - 2010

PhD Program in Mathematical Logic | Thesis title: "A two-dimensional semantics for

Rome, Italy

natural language formalization"

Master Degree, Università Degli Studi di Genova

2002 - 2007

Italian Master Degree (Laurea Magistrale) – Mathematics

Genova, Italy

Certificates

TOEFL

Test date: 2020

Score: 98/120 (Advanced)

PCAP - Certified Associate in Python Programming

ID: 383260354

Validation: 338962730

Score: 92%

Projects

AGReATWine, Contributor □

2020 - present

Creation of a database of Italian wines included in DOCG appellations, evaluated by the three main national wine guides

KDE, Contributor, Member ☑

2005 - present

Code, designs and translations for many desktop applications and web applications from the KDE ecosystem.

ArchLinux, *Package mantainer* □

2005 - present

Arch Linux is a Linux distribution that tries to Keep It Simple

GSConnect, Contributor ☑

Complete implementation of KDE Connect especially for GNOME Shell.

InvoicePlane, *Contributor* □

A self-hosted open source application for managing your invoices, clients and payments.

RAMP, Contributor

Ramp is a python library for rapid prototyping of machine learning solutions. It's a light-weight pandas-based machine learning framework pluggable with existing python machine learning and statistics tools.

Wiki.js, *Patch contributor* □

Wiki.js is a modern and powerful wiki app built on Node.js

Publications

Collana UnidTest, Libri per la preparazione dei test di ammissione universitari

Other certificates

Italian Sommelier Association - Diploma

01/2020

Diploma di Sommelier rilasciato dall'Associazione Italiana Sommelier

Bologna, Italy